# KYLE VAN BERGEN

Seattle, WA 98117

480-330-4100 • kyleavb@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/kylevanbergen

### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

Enthusiastic and result-driven professional with over five years of information technology and code consulting experience. Avid gamer and tech enthusiast with knowledge of virtual reality and the Unity game engine . Motivated life-long learner looking to pivot my previous experiences into web development and to further my understanding of complex platforms and enhance my experience with various technology stacks.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS & COMPUTER LANGUAGES

- Languages & Databases: JavaScript, C#, Python, CSS, HTML, SQL, JSX, EJS, MongoDB, PostgreSQL
- Framework & Libraries: React, Redux, Node.js, Express, Django, jQuery, bCrypt, Materialize, Bootstrap
- ORM Tools: Mongoose, Sequelize
- Other: Unity, Canvas, Socket.io, Git, Github, Ajax, Heroku, RESTful, Azure, AWS

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# General Assembly, Seattle, WA

April 2018 - Present

Instructional Associate

- Prepare and develop lessons for implementation and usage of JavaScript, Python, SQL, and React.
- Create traininging and coding examples in Github to showcase suitable web development practices.
- Provide regular code review to students on the use of JavaScript and Python.
- Lead standup meeting during project weeks to make sure student projects are appropriately scoped and progressing to MVP.

### Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ

August 2016 - December 2017

IT Help Desk Supervisor

- Managed a team of 10 IT specialists to deliver technical support to students and faculty.
- Created and implemented a coaching initiative to improve quality and speed of service to clients.
- Devloped a comprehensive analytical program to query existing data using JavaScript and SQL to identify pain points within the department and improve coverage.
- Provided training and supervision of new employees to ensure quality of service, improve team efficiency and productivity.

### IMPRIVA, Los Angeles, CA

August 2012 - February 2016

JavaScript Report Developer

- Solved problems using JavaScript, HTML and/or SQL to present solutions to project stake holders.
- Provided project leadership, guidance, and support to the team of business process consultants and client owners.
- Improved, modified, and upgraded the designs and functionalities of reports by refactoring JavaScript for stakeholders.

### **EDUCATION**

**General Assembly,** Seattle, WA **Web Development Immersive Program** 

May 2018

**Mesa Community College,** Mesa, AZ **Associates Degree** 

May 2009